JAY FALIA

Electrical Automation Engineer and HR Manager

Address: 21-Digvijay Plot, Jamnagar, Pin-361005 Mobile: 9408323910

Email-ID: jayfalia50@gmail.com

Web: https://jayfalia.github.io/resume/

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/jay-falia-8849061a5

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Dedicated, professional, and experienced electrical engineer who has been in the field for nearly 3 years. Proficient in a wide variety of engineering software. Excellent working knowledge of safety codes and experience of installation, commissioning, plant maintenance, programming, testing and troubleshooting of electrical panels/machines. Well versed in the creation of internal communication and external professional documents and can liaise with all levels of staff/clients to provide the support needed in achieving planned work/goal.

EXPERIENCE

PGVCL, Jamnagar — Apprentice Junior Engineer

NOV 2020 - PRESENT

Preparing proposal files and helping customers in getting the new electrical connections or load extensions or load reduction.

SAFCON, Jamnagar — Electrical Technician

AUG 2020 - NOV 2020

Testing of existing old wiring, repairing/replacement of old broken/faulty gadgets, preventive maintenance of panels and electrical equipment, identifying circuit faults, and solving electrical tripping problems.

GSECL, Jamnagar — Degree Apprentice

MAY 2019 - AUG 2020

All kinds of maintenance work of 220KV switchyard and panels of the control room. Testing of different electrical equipment like a relay, CT, PT, transformers, etc.

Air Diagnostic & Engineering LLP, All over India — Service Engineer

FEB 2018 - JUN 2019

Installation, commissioning, and maintenance of HVAC machines. Maintaining customer-client relationship

SKILLS

- PLC Programming.
- AUTOCAD Designing.
- SCADA Designing & Programming.
- Hardware Wiring.
- HMI Designing & System Integration.
- VFD Integrations.
- Troubleshooting of Panels/Machines.
- Conflict Management
- Critical Listener
- Time And Work Management
- Arduino Programming and Wiring.

EDUCATION

SYMBIOSIS UNIVERSITY PGD-HRM (2019-2021)

SCORE: 73.76%

VIDITRI TECH HUB AUTOMATION ENGINEER (2019-2020)

GRADE: A

ICA EDU SKILLS PVT. LTD. SOLAR TECHNICIAN (2018-2019)

GRADE: B

V.V.P ENGINEERING COLLEGE B.E-ELECTRICAL (2014-2018) SCORE: 76.6% (CGPA - 8.15)

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, and Gujarati